HARI PRASAD REDDY

+91 730-620-3432

hariprasadreddytech@gmail.com

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II

Ananthapur, Andhra Pradesh https://www.linkedin.com/in/h ari-prasad-reddy-t/

SUMMARY

Qualified and professional SDE II with 4.6 years of experience in Java Backend Development. Passionate about software engineering and dedicated to implementing best practices. Equipped with a strong skill set and experience in agile development environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java 8+

Spring Boot

SQL & MongoDB

Redis

Microservices

Kubernates

- Algorithms
- Data Sructures
- Jenkins Cloud (AWS)

Kafka

Design Patterns

WORK EXPERIENCE

Informatica

SDE II • May 2021 - Mar 2022

- Developed the functionality for publishing prepared enterprise data.
- Prepared Structured and unstructured data preparation and data recipes.
- Develop and execute unit tests and perform system testing to ensure software quality.
- Implemented latest Spring Boot versions in services.

Attra

Sr. Software Engineer • July 2017 - Feb 2021

- Implemented taxes and service charges on purchase transactions.
- Built Spend Limits feature for payment products.
- Developed partial and full reversals of payment transactions.
- Contributed to the Upgrade and maintain of web services.

SOFT SKILLS

- Excellent Communication Skills
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- Strong Problem-Solving Abilities
- Product and Customer-Centric Mindset

AWARDS AND HONORS

SPOT Award for Best Performance in team

SPOT Award for building test report utility

Attra • 2019

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science & Engg

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Hyderabad • 2013–2017

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Database Fundamentals